[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a55", "question": "What was the name of the Uncle Bill's butler on \"Family Affair\"?", "answer": "Mr. French", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c23f", "question": "What do peacocks mate with?", "answer": "Peahens", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f4fdff048f679a45aacf", "question": "Mysophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Dirt and germs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339656", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Marge develops a serious case of what when she gets behind the wheel of her new Canyonero?", "answer": "Road rage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baa6", "question": "Who was credited with developing the original recipe for Angostura Bitters?", "answer": "Dr. Johann Gottlieb Benjamin Siegert", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398bb", "question": "Who is Mufasa's son in Disney's movie \"The Lion King\"?", "answer": "Simba", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b832", "question": "What would a sommelier recommend to you?", "answer": "Wine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d1", "question": "Which two numbers are used in the binary system?", "answer": "Zero and one", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133888e", "question": "What is Dennis the Menace's last name?", "answer": "Mitchell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59636e8e967692ea851899b3", "question": "On average, we spend 6 months of our lives waiting for what?", "answer": "Traffic lights to change", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d0", "question": "Who opened the first \"cinema\" in Paris in 1895?", "answer": "The Lumiere Brothers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062ba7c9d816e292245c22", "question": "What is the name of Captain Ahab's ship?", "answer": "The Pequod", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a09c20565ad31a57c797", "question": "What was the Liberty Bell originally called?", "answer": "The State House Bell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59049c60cf93664eb10486a6", "question": "What is the fear of the number 13 known as?", "answer": "Triskaidekaphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133963b", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Faline?", "answer": "Bambi's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4c3", "question": "What name is given to the unit of electrical resistance?", "answer": "Ohm", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a272", "question": "Who played the character of Corie Bratter in the 1967 film \"Barefoot in the Park\"?", "answer": "Jane Fonda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a271", "question": "Who played the character of Paul Bratter in the 1967 film \"Barefoot in the Park\"?", "answer": "Robert Redford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c234", "question": "What do Teal Pumpkins represent to Trick or Treaters?", "answer": "Non-Food Treats", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd667e3a5bfecdd737e086d", "question": "How old did the oldest recorded person live to be?", "answer": "122-years-old", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf5", "question": "What year was actress Julia Roberts born?", "answer": "1967", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de3", "question": "For what movie did director Fritz Lang himself dub the whistling for star Peter Lorre?", "answer": "M", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb60865dad637d903c882a", "question": "Off what country are the islands of Islay, Mull, and St. Kilda located?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a969", "question": "What California peak, which erupted in 1915, is the world's largest lava dome?", "answer": "Lassen Peak", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f6", "question": "Who is the adopted son of Vito Corleone?", "answer": "Tom Hagen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad46", "question": "What US president was known as \"Father of the Constitution\"?", "answer": "James Madison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0cc", "question": "What general led the Mexicans in the siege against the Alamo?", "answer": "Santa Ana", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c6", "question": "What is the most common Scrabble letter?", "answer": "E", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ee", "question": "Who was the first African-American to be appointed as a US Supreme Court justice?", "answer": "Thurgood Marshall", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab1b3a04fda37788a9a1dc4", "question": "What year did Agatha Christie publish the novel \"Sparkling Cyanide\"?", "answer": "1945", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3aa", "question": "Which famous painting was stolen from an Oslo museum in 1994?", "answer": "The Scream", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff51d01ff04d658268c9321", "question": "In addition to his wife, who was seated with him when Abraham Lincoln was assassinated?", "answer": "Clara Harris and Henry Rathbone.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59523cc5736d4be723796b3a", "question": "Which city is home to the Blue Jays baseball team?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea47c3ff048f679a45abad", "question": "What strangely named type of mackerel is also known as an Ono in Hawaii?", "answer": "Wahoo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c90d0ee52800b05cac20f0f", "question": "What is Eisoptrophobia?", "answer": "The fear of mirrors", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bde", "question": "Which fictional criminal has a sidekick called Bunny?", "answer": "Raffles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d4c32596a59cbdfbd3a7", "question": "What is the most commonly broken human bone?", "answer": "Clavicle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c26c", "question": "How many wings does a flea have?", "answer": "Zero", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b006", "question": "What war gave the US its freedom from Britain?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390d1", "question": "What year did Robert Burns write the poem \"Auld Lange Syne\"?", "answer": "1788", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b6f", "question": "Who wrote the novel series \"The Green Mile\"?", "answer": "Stephen King", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab6c", "question": "What year did Bangladesh become independent from Pakistan?", "answer": "1971", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b23", "question": "What book was Mark David Chapman carrying when he shot John Lennon?", "answer": "The Catcher in the Rye", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6008df93f4f3bc4a292f862c", "question": "What does Passover commemorate?", "answer": "It commemorates how Moses safely led the Jews out of Egypt, where they had spent centuries living in slavery under the Pharaohs.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b756", "question": "What team did basketball star Larry Bird play 13 seasons for?", "answer": "Boston Celtics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015f975fe83fe1f2a824c33", "question": "What does the final day of Passover celebrate?", "answer": "The arrival of the Israelites to the Red Sea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e11", "question": "What American literary character's real name is Lula Mae Barnes?", "answer": "Holly Golightly", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a77", "question": "What former NFL star was the author of a book about needlepoint for men?", "answer": "Rosey Grier", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339787", "question": "What wrestler supplied the torso for the Scorpion King in the movie \"The Mummy Returns\"?", "answer": "The Rock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c808", "question": "What popular aquarium fish is known as pla-kad in its native Thailand?", "answer": "The Siamese fighting fish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe0e3affcbed638185eaa24", "question": "A building called \"The Gherkin\" graces which city's skyline?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba5", "question": "What novel, written by E.B. White, tells the story of an adopted mouse?", "answer": "Stuart Little", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba0d", "question": "What fast food chain was founded by Colonel Harland Sanders?", "answer": "Kentucky Fried Chicken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c62c", "question": "Which planet is referred to as the planet of oceans?", "answer": "Earth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5efa93f1ccb363a2cbc52278", "question": "What is the largest landlocked county in England?", "answer": "Shropshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb0", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Bloody Mary?", "answer": "Tomato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c378", "question": "What tool did Charles Moncke invent?", "answer": "The monkey wrench", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffcfed09dc5ec6cd98a832c", "question": "What writer had more than 70 different pen names?", "answer": "Lauran Bosworth Paine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b81c", "question": "What color blazer is presented to the Masters golf winner?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339afb", "question": "What rock musician got his stage name from the yellow and black jerseys he used to wear?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b82a", "question": "How many instruments accompany someone singing \"a cappella\"?", "answer": "None", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8d7532b42d4a3561a9f0c", "question": "In which country would you find the Gruta Canabrava cave?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab13", "question": "Hobart is the capital of which Australian state?", "answer": "Tasmania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6010c1620775fa611bce67c3", "question": "Dysmorphia is a mental disorder characterized by what?", "answer": "The obsessive idea that some aspect of one's own body part or appearance is severely flawed. The obsessive idea that some aspect of one's own body part or appearance is severely flawed, and therefore, warrants exceptional measures to hide or fix it", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338907", "question": "What Canadian Island was the setting for \"Anne of Green Gables\"?", "answer": "Prince Edward Island", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a974", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Duma?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f42", "question": "What song is, appropriately , attributed to a seventeenth-century composer, Dr. John Bull?", "answer": "God Save the King/Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b116", "question": "Who was the second man to set foot on the moon?", "answer": "Edwin \"Buzz\" Aldrin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59db77d30ab2c8f322317fef", "question": "What country does motor racing's Jacques Villeneuve come from?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5cfe6ce05a3942286e28", "question": "Which iconic \u201880s role required training from a professional mime?", "answer": "\"Robocop\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600b880a1d8c1817608d53ed", "question": "In mathematics, what term describes the bottom number in a fraction?", "answer": "Denominator", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e94d0ff5ea27d7a1303aed3", "question": "Is the cucumber a fruit or a vegetable?", "answer": "Fruit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5971dd5089261e916c8e099d", "question": "At what wind speed does a tropical storm become a hurricane?", "answer": "74mph (119km/hr)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd2", "question": "Rhea and Cronus were the parents of what king of the Greek gods?", "answer": "Zeus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399fc", "question": "What 1992 film features the characters Colonel Nathan Jessup and Lieutenant Daniel Kaffee?", "answer": "A Few Good Men", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338944", "question": "In Greek mythology, what is the name of the staff carried by Hermes?", "answer": "The Caduceus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ef", "question": "What flavor was the original filling in Twinkies?", "answer": "Banana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b358c355db0d66a186cb55c", "question": "Popular in the Balkans, what type of beverage is the \"Rakia\"?", "answer": "Fruit brandy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b7", "question": "Which Actor played Chachi Arcola on the TV show \"Happy Days\"?", "answer": "Scott Baio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb5", "question": "What rock star caused a stir in 2007 when he said that he'd snorted his late father's cremains?", "answer": "Keith Richards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008dd25f4f3bc4a292f861e", "question": "Mother Teresa received the Nobel Peace Prize for what?", "answer": "Peace, or more accurately \"for work undertaken in the struggle to overcome poverty and distress, which also constitutes a threat to peace\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b64d", "question": "Irish coffee is made with what type of alcohol?", "answer": "Whiskey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd9c97e83c707845b217d", "question": "According to legend, which music star did Michael Jordan once chastise for wearing the sneakers of a rival player/company?", "answer": "Bow Wow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b05", "question": "What year was Charles Darwin's work, \"On the Origin of Species\", published?", "answer": "1859", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339501", "question": "What year was the movie \"Titanic\" released?", "answer": "1997", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133993e", "question": "Which Spice Girl married to soccer star David Beckham in 1999?", "answer": "Posh Spice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339076", "question": "Nut, or Neuth, was the Egyptian goddess of what?", "answer": "Sky", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5af25d94b63e5727cf5a4866", "question": "What year did Elton John originally release the song \"Candle in the Wind\"?", "answer": "1974", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015fc7cfe83fe1f2a824c41", "question": "According to Greek mythology, who was the Greek god of music?", "answer": "Apollo is the god of music as well as archery, poetry, healing, prophecy, manly beauty, plague, knowledge and arts.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339228", "question": "What is \"Shawshank\" in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "A prison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c559", "question": "What color eggs do peacocks lay?", "answer": "They don't lay eggs - peacocks are male peafowl. Peahens are female and lay eggs.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b3d", "question": "Who painted \"The Haywain Triptych\"?", "answer": "Hieronymus Bosch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b658", "question": "What baseball great was nicknamed the Iron Man?", "answer": "Cal Ripken Jr.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe1f165145fb29466707392", "question": "As used in English, what is the meaning of the Latin phrase \"caveat emptor\"?", "answer": "Let the buyer beware", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba93", "question": "In a standard deck of cards, the Jack, Queen, and King all show both eyes in what suit?", "answer": "Clubs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b02", "question": "The ending vocal riff of what 1966 Frank Sinatra song inspired the name of cartoon character dog Scooby-Doo?", "answer": "Strangers in the Night", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c702", "question": "What planet is named for the Roman equivalent of the Greek god Zeus?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c085", "question": "What is another name for the eggplant?", "answer": "Aubergine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b0", "question": "Who played the role of Andy Dufresne in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Tim Robbins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a440", "question": "Which country is home to the Great Barrier Reef?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7cc", "question": "What bird is Britain's VTOL \"jump jet\" named for?", "answer": "The Harrier hawk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f6", "question": "What planet has a storm system called the \"Great Red Spot\"?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ee", "question": "What organization in the Harry Potter series is named after Dumbledore's patronus?", "answer": "Order of the Phoenix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be81", "question": "Who was given a gift of a hat pin and a copy of \"Leaves of Grass\" on February 28, 1997?", "answer": "Monica Lewinsky", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ba", "question": "What year did MTV debut as a channel?", "answer": "1981", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a083", "question": "Kevin Bacon, Alfre Woodard, and Queen Latifah starred in which 2005 spin-off of the film \"Barbershop\"?", "answer": "Beauty Shop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ced", "question": "What artist performed the song titled \"Be-Bop-a-Lula\"?", "answer": "Gene Vincent", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000ef089a72b906b34e3cf8", "question": "What is the product of a body\u2019s mass and its linear velocity?", "answer": "Momentum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10e", "question": "During WWI, what disease caused 1/3 of all soldier's deaths?", "answer": "Spanish Flu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7b3", "question": "Edam cheese originated in which country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b48", "question": "Whose epitaph reads: \"Quoth the Raven nevermore\"?", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb64f25dad637d903c8832", "question": "Where is the world's longest golf course?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a82620565ad31a57c7f4", "question": "What vegetable did British cooks substitute for bananas during World War II?", "answer": "Parsnips", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea34c4ff048f679a45aafb", "question": "What animal's fingerprints resembles a human's the closest?", "answer": "Koala", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c902fbde8045e48466e6", "question": "Which farm animal sleeps standing up?", "answer": "Horses are the only farm animal that can sleep standing up, and it's due to the unique way their legs are structured.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f70f0a9e54d890926f6d9", "question": "Who created the design for Mount Rushmore?", "answer": "Sculptor\u00a0Gutzon Borglum\u00a0created the design and oversaw the project's execution from 1927 to 1941 with his son,\u00a0Lincoln's help.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1b9", "question": "Boxer John L. Sullivan is often recognized as the first what?", "answer": "Heavyweight Champion in gloved boxing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f0bdff048f679a45aaa5", "question": "Tachophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Speed", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c719", "question": "The kingfish is actually the largest species of what type of fish?", "answer": "Mackerel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b1", "question": "What good little witch is Casper's friend?", "answer": "Wendy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b69915ae762b54eb9be9418", "question": "Which team did Babe Ruth join in 1920?", "answer": "The New York Yankees", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca18", "question": "What is a theodolite used for?", "answer": "Surveys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecc23eec223966ae8f8873", "question": "Razzie awards are meant to go to bad movies, but who got nominated for directing the now widely respected film Scarface?", "answer": "Brian De Palma", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a59", "question": "What book starts with the line \"Call me Ishmael.\"?", "answer": "Moby-Dick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf2", "question": "Hydrosis is the medical term for what?", "answer": "Sweating", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fffa6a173838c5c8a417f30", "question": "How many teeth does an aardvark have?", "answer": "None", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e13", "question": "What ballet features the famous \"pas de deux\" between the Sugar-Plum Fairy and a cavalier?", "answer": "The Nutcracker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0af", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Beggars Banquet\"?", "answer": "Rolling Stones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c71", "question": "Who wrote the 1976 novel \"Interview with the Vampire\"?", "answer": "Ann Rice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5909d015bb53d1af658864f8", "question": "Who directed the 1946 film \"It\u2019s a Wonderful Life\"?", "answer": "Frank Capra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfc5c9dc5ec6cd98a831b", "question": "Who painted \"The Birth of Venus\"?", "answer": "Sandro Botticelli", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf6", "question": "In which movie did Billie Burke portray a witch?", "answer": "The Wizard of Oz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff511c7ff04d658268c92ca", "question": "How did Mary Ludwig Hays earn the nickname \"Molly Pitcher\"?", "answer": "During the Battle of Monmouth, she attended to the Revolutionary soldiers by\u00a0bringing them water, often under heavy fire.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133914e", "question": "Who was the Greek god of craftsmen?", "answer": "Hephaestus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8de", "question": "What animals teeth were used as knife blades by Natives?", "answer": "Beaver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c302", "question": "Which media is read from the inside out, compact discs or vinyl records?", "answer": "Compact discs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf7", "question": "What is the best known artificial international language?", "answer": "Esperanto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e90", "question": "What was Fox's first series to win a TV season's Nielsen ratings?", "answer": "American Idol", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b596", "question": "Which building has been nicknamed \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "GE Building", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afea", "question": "The Battle of Bull Run occurred during what war?", "answer": "Civil War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f8", "question": "What year did Volkswagen introduce the Golf R32 model?", "answer": "2002", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af25b9fb63e5727cf5a485a", "question": "Which English band had the hit song \"Unbelievable\"?", "answer": "EMF", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc10cec223966ae8f8864", "question": "In the 2007 Superbowl, a player used what piece of equipment to make a catch?", "answer": "Helmet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338928", "question": "Which rock group charted \"Land of Confusion\" in 1986?", "answer": "Genesis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a854", "question": "Machu Picchu is also known as what?", "answer": "Lost City of the Incas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5937eea308d98002fdd633d6", "question": "\"Confide in Me\" was a hit in 1994 for which singer?", "answer": "Kylie Minogue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7ce67877e98cb97778a41", "question": "What is the oldest major city in the Philippines?", "answer": "Cebu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a3", "question": "What was B.J.'s full name in the TV show \"B.J. and the Bear\"?", "answer": "Billie Joe McKay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba45", "question": "What is the official state dessert of Massachusetts?", "answer": "Boston Cream Pie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339372", "question": "In the movie \"Batman\", what does the Joker call his secret ingredient?", "answer": "Smylex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d3f22596a59cbdfbd39f", "question": "Who is Ada Lovelace?", "answer": "The first computer programmer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b90e", "question": "What 2 letters are often used as a written abbreviation for \"hugs and kisses\"?", "answer": "XO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff517fcff04d658268c92fe", "question": "By which nickname is Henry McCarty better known?", "answer": "Billy the Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea7", "question": "What was the surname of Nicholas II, the last tsar of Russia?", "answer": "Romanov", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febd4ca7e83c707845b2160", "question": "In the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\", which character had his hands replaced by the director, Frank Darabont, as insert shot?", "answer": "Andy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa7", "question": "Honshu is the largest island of which country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c035", "question": "Who invented the Spinning Jenny?", "answer": "James Hargreaves", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c283", "question": "How often are brain cells replaced?", "answer": "Never", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac34", "question": "What is the first word of the text of the US Constitution?", "answer": "We", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaed", "question": "Dodoma is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Tanzania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c094", "question": "What are Common Darter and Southern Hawker types of?", "answer": "Dragonflies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cf85877e98cb97778a4f", "question": "What is the state bird of Mississippi?", "answer": "Northern Mockingbird", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69f1720565ad31a57c78a", "question": "The first woman to run for president chose whom as her running mate?", "answer": "Fredrick Douglas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6996320565ad31a57c745", "question": "According to the Bible, who was the father of Arphaxad?", "answer": "Shem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c09c", "question": "What wine barrel contains 126 gallons?", "answer": "Pipe or butt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a95d", "question": "What is Hungary's capital?", "answer": "Budapest", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c8", "question": "Who created the character Hercule Poirot?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c999", "question": "Which mole-like mammal has given its name to a mean spirited or bad tempered woman?", "answer": "Shrew\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b144", "question": "Who did Muhammad Ali defeat to gain the World Heavyweight boxing title for the first time?", "answer": "Sonny Liston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febaeee7e83c707845b20f9", "question": "What gives eyes their color?", "answer": "Melanin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63b", "question": "Which blood type is a universal? donor", "answer": "O negative", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f16a4af7c52aae91cc07da", "question": "Who is Prospero's daughter in Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\"?", "answer": "Miranda", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c6c1fbde8045e48466b9", "question": "Which naturally occurring element is heaviest by atomic weight?", "answer": "Uranium -- At present, ununoctium is the heaviest but it's man-made, and so disqualified as a \"naturally\" occurring element.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bb356202627b8fe95581bdd", "question": "As of 2014, which country is the location of the second highest flagpole in the world after Saudi Arabia built a taller one in Jeddah?", "answer": "Tajikistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590682eaff9c0647b50a80a2", "question": "What popular mobile game, that caused many players to get into accidents, was released in July of 2016?", "answer": "Pokemon Go", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a746", "question": "Nevada is nicknamed the \"Silver State\" in honor of what?", "answer": "Silver mines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb88", "question": "What gun manufacturer's first names were Horace and Daniel?", "answer": "Smith & Wesson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad9", "question": "In 1997, what country singer formed the band, The Ranch, with two fellow Australian musicians?", "answer": "Keith Urban", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9de", "question": "Bubble Wrap was invented while researchers were trying to make what?", "answer": "Wallpaper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd0", "question": "What TV show did \"Fraiser\" spin off from?", "answer": "Cheers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399eb", "question": "How many of the seven dwarfs had mustaches?", "answer": "None", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008db85f4f3bc4a292f8618", "question": "Who was the first U.S. President born west of the Mississippi River?", "answer": "Herbert Hoover (The country's 31st president, elected in 1928, was born in 1874 in West Branch, Iowa.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe767a3eec85e375820b293", "question": "What is the largest religious monument in the world?", "answer": "Angkor Wat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb8", "question": "What is the fear of gods or dieties known as?", "answer": "Theophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc11a0469bb8041d07a077", "question": "What Indian spice that grows in pods is used to make chai tea?", "answer": "Cardamom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a1e1ceab5a031299b745736", "question": "Who saved Andromeda from the sea monster?", "answer": "Perseus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feddbc66ce05a3942286d94", "question": "For what film did Meryl Streep win her first Oscar?", "answer": "\"Kramer Vs. Kramer\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed1", "question": "The eggs of what sturgeon are the preferred form of caviar?", "answer": "Beluga", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d1", "question": "What year did tennis player Martina Navratilova turn pro?", "answer": "1975", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e7", "question": "What was ALF's girlfriend from Melmac's name?", "answer": "Rhonda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e983aebfabb9c85d8a96a", "question": "Which novel by Michael Crichton was a best selling paperback in 1993?", "answer": "Jurassic Park", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395cf", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \"Parades just bring out so many emotions in me\" joy, excitement, looking...\"?", "answer": "Marge Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aef9", "question": "What US president was nicknamed \"Honest Abe\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb0737e83c707845b2104", "question": "Which two gems are different colors of the same mineral?", "answer": "Ruby and sapphire", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b81", "question": "Who played Jill Taylor on the TV show \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Patricia Richardson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3924c73aa70ea0b70ad8", "question": "Explorers named Rhode Island after resemblance to which part of the world?", "answer": "The Greek island, Rhodes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f47342cfb6472aeed499d5", "question": "What is a \"Papoose\"?", "answer": "A Native American Child", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb8f", "question": "What kind of animal is pictured on the wrapper of a Klondike bar?", "answer": "Polar bear", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e93306d333868d34d752", "question": "Where did the world's first commercial flight travel to?", "answer": "St. Petersburg to Tampa, Florida", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f0b", "question": "Which of the six stars of the TV sitcom \"Friends\" is the eldest?", "answer": "Lisa Kudrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a988761d1b4d384d5d68d", "question": "How many seasons did the TV show \"Bonanza\" have before going off the air in 1973?", "answer": "14", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c203", "question": "Which country were the 1900 Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba6f4874c93a3298b215e", "question": "What is Paul Stanley's persona name in the band KISS?", "answer": "The Starchild", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e20", "question": "What popular movie website took its name from a John Travolta line in the movie \"Broken Arrow\"?", "answer": "Ain't It Cool News", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078b7a0eee65b76b9f2669", "question": "Which dung beetle was worshipped by the ancient Egyptians?", "answer": "Scarab", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c245877e98cb97778988", "question": "What is the most populous city in the Middle East?", "answer": "Cairo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fb1", "question": "Comedy band Tenacious D took its name from what sportcaster's catchphrase for good defence?", "answer": "Marv Albert's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6017375e44491cbd7c5a1789", "question": "Who designed and built the interior structure of the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "The innovative designer and builder Gustave Eiffel and his structural engineer, Maurice Koechlin designed and built the statue.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df6", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek god Ares?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb9", "question": "What soft drink used the ad slogan \"Obey your thirst\" for almost two decades?", "answer": "Sprite", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133920e", "question": "What rock band is led by Michael Stripe?", "answer": "R.E.M.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af2", "question": "What 1950's rock pioneer was portrayed by Lou Diamond Phillips in a 1987 film?", "answer": "Ritchie Valens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a83c", "question": "How many US states border Ohio?", "answer": "5", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c46", "question": "What city's \"Tin Pan Alley\" was known for its music publishing industry?", "answer": "New York", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe69b2420565ad31a57c75c", "question": "Which World War II battle saw the greatest number of tanks used in world history?", "answer": "The Battle of Kursk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff2148831a458464a93c458", "question": "A sentence, verse, etc., that includes all the letters of the alphabet is called what?", "answer": "Pangram", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf6b", "question": "In the game \"Joust\", what animal was your mount?", "answer": "An Ostritch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a96a", "question": "Gouda and Edam are cities in what country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c9", "question": "What year did Apple introduce its first retail store?", "answer": "2001", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b8", "question": "What holds the bit in a drill?", "answer": "Chuck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339313", "question": "What did the license plate read on the team's response vehicle in the movie \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Ecto-1", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c493", "question": "What animal has been dubbed nature's skyscraper?", "answer": "The giraffe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb65", "question": "What horse won the 2012 Kentucky Derby and Preakness Stakes?", "answer": "I'll Have Another", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1e", "question": "What key is to the right of T on a standard keyboard?", "answer": "Y", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc7e", "question": "What Sanskrit word do Buddhists use to refer to the endless cycle of birth, death, and rebirth?", "answer": "Samsara", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff3c29e4f032c0db195b483", "question": "Who served as chief minister to King Henry VIII of England from 1532 to 1540?", "answer": "Thomas Cromwell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b918e662d71a5365102c", "question": "\"The Color Purple\" begins, \"You better not tell nobody but\" who?", "answer": "God", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b44d", "question": "What world leader was assassinated in Cairo on October 6, 1981?", "answer": "Anwar Sadat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c20c", "question": "Which country hosted the first Olympic Games after World War I?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc9176de0eb824d405301", "question": "Where is the New York City Marathon start line?", "answer": "Staten Island -- It starts at the base of the Verrazano-Narrows Bridge in Staten Island and ends in Central Park.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b464", "question": "Boxer John L. Sullivan is often recognized as the first what?", "answer": "Heavyweight Champion in gloved boxing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d91", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Sabotage\" based on?", "answer": "The Secret Agent", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c854", "question": "What nation is home to the Komodo dragon?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fcb", "question": "What movie featured the fictional band \"The Soggy Bottom Boys\"?", "answer": "O Brother, Where Art Thou?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba2d6874c93a3298b2135", "question": "Which Italian won the 1998 Tour de France bicycle race?", "answer": "Marco Pantani", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b6990e4e762b54eb9be9415", "question": "What standard temperature in Celsius is used by the Normal Temperature and Pressure (NTP) standard?", "answer": "20 C", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c36c", "question": "What sign of the zodiac is the first air sign of the calender year?", "answer": "Aquarius", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339412", "question": "On the \"Abbey Road\" album cover, which member of the Beatles is on the far left?", "answer": "George Harrison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339163", "question": "Who created the cartoon TV show \"Futurama\"?", "answer": "Matt Groening", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0e184fcbed638185eaa1b", "question": "What three countries intersect at Mount Roraima?", "answer": "Venezuela, Brazil, and Guyana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2dc", "question": "Avian flu in China led to 2006 price hikes in what piece of sporting equipment?", "answer": "Badminton birdies", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c502fbde8045e48466a5", "question": "What is chionophobia?", "answer": "Fear of snow.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab52", "question": "Ljubljana is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Slovenia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9bc", "question": "What does \"Honolulu\" translate to in English?", "answer": "Sheltered harbor", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe93ccf6bd93ce3a4e5f6ac", "question": "What is the smallest biological unit of a living organism?", "answer": "Cell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2dd", "question": "What is the fastest flying butterfly?", "answer": "Skipper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be1", "question": "What year was Elvis born in?", "answer": "1935", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c847", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the cornea?", "answer": "The eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b3c", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Margaret Mitchell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389ea", "question": "What is by far the most famous New York-based piece of work by French sculptor Auguste Bartholdi?", "answer": "The Statue of Liberty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7e7b2b24f84e0b9f9ffbc", "question": "How many states comprise Australia?", "answer": "Six", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eb0f6f83302ff91e464a2", "question": "What company makes the Vince Lombardi Trophy?", "answer": "Tiffany & Co.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d2", "question": "What was Murray Langston better known as to the public?", "answer": "The Unknown Comic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6aa7020565ad31a57c818", "question": "What was the name of the airplane that Charles Lindbergh used to make his famous solo flight across the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "The Spirit of St Louis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba71e874c93a3298b2161", "question": "What is Ace Frehley\u2019s persona name in the band KISS?", "answer": "Spaceman or Space Ace", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a1e1d75b5a031299b74573b", "question": "The Okapi is native to which African country?", "answer": "Congo", "category": "geography"}]